sydneyoperahouse.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy - Sydney Opera House

**1\. How is personal information collected?  
**  
Sydney Opera House offers customers the ability to purchase tickets and make philanthropic donations through various channels including:

  * Sydney Opera House’s Contact Centre.
  * Sydney Opera House’s philanthropy department.
  * In person at a Sydney Opera House Box Office.
  * Sydney Opera House’s websites and mobile applications.
  * Authorised ticketing agencies and partners.

Sydney Opera House also provides an Insiders Membership programme, e-newsletters, conducts competitions and other promotional activities, and communicates with customers through various online and electronic media.

These channels reflect the main methods through which Sydney Opera House may collect personal information about customers and prospective customers. We may also collect information about you at other times you engage with us (e.g. when you attend an event at Sydney Opera House or an event presented by us).

Sydney Opera House may also collect information from third parties, for example from Organisations (refer to section 4 below) who take bookings for performances at Sydney Opera House.

Collection of information will occur at the time you provide details to Sydney Opera House or its authorised agents or, in the case of electronic services, when you use our electronic services to obtain information or transact with us.

Sydney Opera House operates closed circuit television (CCTV). Cameras located in public areas are in public view as far as possible, having regard to heritage values.  

**2\. The kinds of personal information that Sydney Opera House collects**

If you wish to purchase tickets, join Sydney Opera House Insiders or make a donation to Sydney Opera House through any channel, we may request or require you to provide information including your name, mailing address, email address, telephone contacts and other personal identifying information. The primary reason we request or require this information is so we can contact you in the event of performance postponement or cancellation, or when other important information must be provided, for example, difficulties relating to your purchase or philanthropic transaction. We also collect address information in order to deliver tickets to you. In some circumstances we may collect health information from you.

If you browse Sydney Opera House's website we may use cookies to track your browsing activities. See section 9 below.

When you engage in transactional online activities on the Sydney Opera House website, we will ask you to provide personal information. Some fields are optional, others are required in order for you to make a transaction.

When you visit a Sydney Opera House website, our web servers make a record of your visit and log the following information:

  * Your computer's unique internet address.
  * The date and time of your visit.
  * The pages you accessed and documents downloaded.
  * The previous website you have visited to find our website - via search engine or a link on another website.
  * The type of browser and operating system you are using.
  * The amount of time spent on our website.
  * Your geographic location, type of device used, repeat visits.

This provides us with information about how the website is used and navigated, including number of visits, and the frequency and duration of visits. We may combine this information with information you have already provided to us to help us understand more about your preferences and interests.

If you use our WiFi service, we may also log your location and your MAC address. Please read to the WiFi terms and conditions provided before you access Sydney Opera House WiFi.

We may collect information about you from third parties authorised to act on your behalf. For example, if a parent, guardian, friend or associate purchases tickets for you.

We may collect health information with your consent if the information is reasonably necessary to ensure your health, safety or access during visits to our venues.

If you do not provide the required data with respect to a particular activity, you may not be able to complete your transaction with us, we may not be able to communicate with you when necessary or we may be prevented from providing you with the relevant service. If you do not want to provide us with your personal information, you can remain anonymous by purchasing your tickets at the box office.

If you visit our facilities we may collect footage that includes your image on our CCTV cameras.  

**3\. The purposes for which your personal information is collected, held and used by Sydney Opera House**

Sydney Opera House may use your personal information to:

(a) conduct business communications for example:

  * providing you with services you have requested;
  * processing and managing your purchase or donation;
  * processing your transaction under the terms of our credit card merchant agreements governing credit card transactions;
  * contacting you if we have difficulties with your transaction;
  * contacting you if events change;
  * sending you your tickets via mail or to your electronic device;
  *  sending you confirmation about your ticket booking, via email or fax;
  *  sending you a receipt for your donation to Sydney Opera House;
  * responding to requests or enquiries made by you;
  * corresponding with you about a competition you have entered;

(b) ensure that you can access the venue of a performance or to help protect your health and safety should an adverse health incident take place while you are visiting the Sydney Opera House;

(c) compile  user profiles to enable Sydney Opera House to improve products and services for its customers;

(d) conduct direct marketing by sending you special offers, news and updates (provided you have not opted out from receiving this material under section 5 below) including, without limitation, the following:

  * sending you marketing material (including, without limitation, requests for feedback and material promoting third party products or services);
  * corresponding with you about a competition;
  * sending you special offers about Sydney Opera House and third party events, merchandise, products or services;
  * conducting research or surveys; 
  * for fundraising purposes;

(e) undertake observations and analysis of audience choices, preferences, behaviour and characteristics both individually and in aggregate;  

(f) for system administration, protection and maintenance including identifying and controlling system abuse and preventing cyber attacks. 

Sydney Opera House uses CCTV to assist with the security and safety of visitors and staff and for the protection and management of our facilities.

**4\. How is your personal information provided to and used by third parties?**

When you book a ticket or donate to Sydney Opera House through any of Sydney Opera House’s channels, or give information to Sydney Opera House for any other purpose, the personal information you provide will be entered into a database.

Our database is a customer relationship management system which is shared by Sydney Opera House and other Australian arts organisations (“Organisations”) who use a common customer relationship system known as Tessitura, for the purpose of ticketing, marketing, fundraising and customer relationship management. The Organisations are able to view your name and contact details (e.g. address, email and phone numbers) when those details are given to Sydney Opera House and entered on the database (“Contact Information”). This is so Sydney Opera House can process your current and future transactions as effectively as possible without asking you to provide the same information repeatedly, and also helps ensure the speed and efficiency of any of your dealings with the Organisations.

The current Organisations are the Australian Chamber Orchestra, Bell Shakespeare Company, Opera Australia and Seymour Theatre Centre.

Contact Information and other personal performance related information (such as performance and seating preferences, history of attendances and any other performance related information) is shared with and used by the presenters (for the avoidance of doubt this may include Organisations, promoters and performing companies), merchandisers, sponsors and other entities related to the events for which you purchase tickets (“Event Related Parties”).

This enables the Event Related Parties to know who has attended the event. Event Related Parties may send you marketing or research material. Event Related Parties may be located overseas.

We may also share with certain media agencies, publishers and partners such as Facebook, Google and Twitter, unique identifiers allocated to you. The unique identifier may be associated with information collected when you post information to us, call us, visit our websites or ticketing counters, use our approved agencies, use our apps, or email or fax us. This is so that we can together, provide you with customised content when you visit certain websites and so we can together provide other visitors to those websites with customised advertising.

If Sydney Opera House provides your personal performance related information to the Event Related Parties, agencies, publishers or partners, these entities are responsible for complying with applicable laws governing how personal information is to be handled.

**5\. When and how can you opt out of receiving marketing from us?  
**  
You may request that you stop receiving marketing communications from Sydney Opera House and that Sydney Opera House stops sharing your information with the presenters of the shows you attend for the purpose of them sending you marketing emails. We will comply with your request but you may also need to opt out from marketing from the presenters.

If you wish to exercise the opt out, you can do so by contacting Sydney Opera House on +61 2 9250 7777, at bookings@sydneyoperahouse.com or, if you have received a marketing email from us, by selecting the ‘Unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of the email.

**6\. Security of personal information  
**  
Sydney Opera House takes reasonable steps to protect all the personal information it receives. Information collected is stored in an appropriately secure format retained in accordance with Sydney Opera House records management policy and CCTV policy. We take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is relevant, accurate and up to date, complete and not misleading. We aim to keep your information for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which it can be lawfully used. Only authorised personnel have access to our customer’s personal information, and work under strict controls and procedures.  

**7\. Are there other circumstances where personal information will be given to anyone else?**

There are some circumstances where Sydney Opera House will need to or be required to disclose personal information about you. We may need to provide third party contractors and service providers with access to your personal information in order to assist us to operate our business or to provide a service to you (e.g. service providers that assist us to send out our mail/email to customers, provide IT services including support of our IT systems, undertake data analysis and analytics, undertake research). If Sydney Opera House engages such contractors and service providers to handle personal information, we require these organisations and service providers to agree to keep your information secure, use it only for the purpose for which it has been provided, handle it in accordance with our directions and return it to us or destroy all copies of it when they have finished, unless they are required by law to retain it. 

There may be other cases where we advise you at the time your personal information is collected that a third party will receive that information (e.g. third parties offering goods or services you have purchased through our website so they can process and fulfil your orders (including contacting you)).

We may disclose information to law enforcement bodies or to meet a legal requirement such as a subpoena.

Otherwise, Sydney Opera House will only disclose personal information if this is required by law, for example under the Government Information (Public Access) Act 2009, permitted under this Customer Privacy Statement, or permitted under the NSW Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998 or the Health Records and Information Privacy Act 2002.  

**7\. Are there other circumstances where personal information will be given to anyone else?**

There are some circumstances where Sydney Opera House will need to or be required to disclose personal information about you. We may need to provide third party contractors and service providers with access to your personal information in order to assist us to operate our business or to provide a service to you (e.g. service providers that assist us to send out our mail/email to customers, provide IT services including support of our IT systems, undertake data analysis and analytics, undertake research). If Sydney Opera House engages such contractors and service providers to handle personal information, we require these organisations and service providers to agree to keep your information secure, use it only for the purpose for which it has been provided, handle it in accordance with our directions and return it to us or destroy all copies of it when they have finished, unless they are required by law to retain it. 

There may be other cases where we advise you at the time your personal information is collected that a third party will receive that information (e.g. third parties offering goods or services you have purchased through our website so they can process and fulfil your orders (including contacting you)).

We may disclose information to law enforcement bodies or to meet a legal requirement such as a subpoena.

Otherwise, Sydney Opera House will only disclose personal information if this is required by law, for example under the Government Information (Public Access) Act 2009, permitted under this Customer Privacy Statement, or permitted under the NSW Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998 or the Health Records and Information Privacy Act 2002.  

**8\. How can you check and update your personal details?  
**  
You have the right to request access and correction of your personal information at any time. If you would like to update or correct your personal details, please contact Sydney Opera House:  
**  
Email:**  [bookings@sydneyoperahouse.com](mailto:bookings@sydneyoperahouse.com) (if you contact us via email, we will confirm your request has been processed)  
**Online:**  existing users may update their details online at Sydney Opera House  
**Telephone:**  +61 2 9250 7777

There are some circumstances under the NSW Privacy and Personal Information Protection Act 1998 when we are not obliged to provide access to the personal information we hold. If one of these situations applies to your request we will let you know.

**9\. Does Sydney Opera House use cookies and web beacons?**

When you visit a Sydney Opera House website, we may store some information commonly known as a “cookie” on your computer. A "cookie" is a small file containing a string of characters that is sent to your computer, tablet, mobile phone or other electronic device when you visit a website. Cookies help Sydney Opera House provide a more customised service (e.g. by storing user preferences in cookies) and helps you get the best out of our websites. They are also used to better understand how people use our websites (e.g. by tracking user trends and patterns of how people navigate our sites). These cookies may be used to collect visitor activity information, manage user log-ins, personal preferences, and provide you with relevant information or customised advertisements. Depending on the browser you use, some of the cookies we use are necessary to enable us to provide services such as selling tickets, goods and other service.

Sydney Opera House websites use both "first party" cookies (cookies used by Sydney Opera House websites only) and "third party" cookies (cookies originating from a third party website). We use first party cookies for storing preferences and data needed throughout your visit to our websites (e.g. managing user log-ins, personal preferences, contents of your shopping cart) and to provide you with customised advertising. We use third party cookies for tracking user trends and patterns with the help of third party web statistics providers. These third party cookies are used exclusively by Sydney Opera House websites and the web statistics provider and are not shared with any other third party. 

In addition, third parties with which Sydney Opera House has relationships, may use cookies to provide you with advertisements that we or they consider are relevant and of interest to you. These third parties include advertisers, advertising networks and technology platforms (e.g. Google AdWords). These third parties may use cookies over which we have no control in order to provide you with customized advertising. For more information we suggest you check the third party’s privacy policy. You can contact Sydney Opera House’s Privacy Contact Officer for a list of current advertising networks and technology platforms used by us.

We also use web beacons (also known as web bugs or clear GIFs) to record the behaviour of users visiting our websites. You can find more detailed information about cookies and web beacons and how they work at [All About Cookies](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/ "All About Cookies website").

If you have downloaded the Sydney Opera House app onto a device, beacons may be used to collect location data about you whilst you are onsite at the Sydney Opera House. This data will allow us to send you notifications about how to find your way around the Sydney Opera House (e.g. to the closest amenities or to the box office) and keep you informed of promotions running on site at that time. Your permission will be sought before this location data is collected.

**10\. Whether we are likely to disclose your information overseas**

We may disclose your information to Event Related Parties. Event Related Parties may be located anywhere in the world depending on the event. 

We may also permit third parties located overseas to use your information in order to provide services to us. When this happens we put in place terms and conditions that ensure that your personal information is protected.

**11\. Changes to this Customer Privacy Statement  
**  
Sydney Opera House’s Customer Privacy Statement may change from time to time.

**12\. How to complain if you are concerned about a breach of privacy by Sydney Opera House  
  **  
If you have any queries or concerns about the way Sydney Opera House has collected, stored, used or disclosed your personal information you should write to us as soon as possible. We will investigate the matters you raise. If you are unhappy with the response you receive from us in response to a complaint you can raise the matter with the NSW Information and Privacy Commission by writing to [ipcinfo@ipc.nsw.gov.au](mailto:ipcinfo@ipc.nsw.gov.au).

Address your correspondence to:  
**  
Privacy Contact Officer  
Sydney Opera House  
GPO Box 4274  
Sydney NSW 2001**

**Or email:**  [privacy@sydneyoperahouse.com](mailto:privacy@sydneyoperahouse.com)

soh.sitemap.redirect.close
